我们将使用 Cloudinary 来处理我们网站上的资产
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: We're gonna use
Cloudinary for handling assets on our site
原因是，如果你观察另一条路径，你会发现
and the reason for that is that
the typical path if you watch the other
在我做的 Frontend Masters 的 Gatsby 工作坊中，我们使用了一个叫做 Sharp 的插件。
Gatsby workshop that I did on Frontend
Masters, we used a plugin called Sharp.
夏普将处理本地的一切，它产生的所有不同的资产作为
And Sharp will handle everything locally,
it generates all the different assets as
构建管道的一部分，并将它们存储在本地文件系统中
part of the build pipeline and
stores them in your local file system and
这次我们不这么做有几个原因。
there are a couple reasons that
we're not gonna do that this time.
第一个是夏普是真正的强大，但
The first one is that Sharp
is really powerful, but
这也是一种挑剔，如果你的节点版本改变或
it's also kind of finicky and
if your node version changes or
如果你的齿轮锁，机器之间有点不同步，然后锋利
if your yarn.lock, it's a little bit
out of sync between machines then sharp
将失败与真正神秘的错误，它可能是有点难以调试。
will fail with really cryptic errors and
it can be kind of hard to debug.
特别是如果你在一个团队里，很多人都会接触到它
Especially if you're on a team where lots
of people are gonna be touching it and
他们不一定使用完全相同的机器设置。
they're not necessarily using
exactly the same machine setup.
所以我们要避免这种麻烦，我们要避免这种混乱。
So we wanna avoid that hassle,
we wanna avoid that confusion.
另一个需要注意的问题是 nulify 刚刚引入了
Another issue that will run into
is that Nullify just introduced
限制免费构建分钟的时间量。
restrictions on the amount of time that
you get for free for build minutes.
所以每次你在那个 Nullify 上运行一个构建，都需要
So every time that you run a build
on that Nullify, it's going to take
他们会根据你每月的总时间来追踪这些账单。
a set amount of time and they track those
bills minutes against your monthly total.
如果你超过了这个月的总数，那么你知道他们不会把你的网站关闭或
If you exceed that monthly total then you
know they don't take your site down or
但是你必须开始支付建设分钟。
anything but you do have to start
paying for building minutes.
这对我们来说意味着，任何我们可以拿走的东西
And what that means for us is that
anything that we can take out of
在不降低我们网站价值的前提下，建设输油管道给了我们一个优势
that build pipeline without degrading
our sites gives us an advantage
让我们正在建造的东西免费，对吗？
to keep stuff that we're building free,
right?
对于个人项目，我们可不想花一大笔钱
And for personal projects we don't wanna
have to be shelling out a bunch of cash
因此 Cloudinary 有一个非常慷慨的免费级别和时间
for that so Cloudinary has an extremely
generous free tier and when
我们使用 Cloudinary 作为资产管理渠道，我们要做两件事。
we use Cloudinary as our asset management
pipeline, we get to do two things.
首先我们把夏普排除在处理流程之外,
First, we dropped Sharp out
of the processing pipeline,
这意味着我们消除了一些神秘的错误和潜在的困惑
which means that we eliminate some cryptic
errors and potential confusion for us and
我们的团队和我们消除额外的工作，在建立过程中完成。
our team and we eliminate extra
work done during the build process.
这将加快我们的构建速度，并减少构建分钟的数量
Which will speed up our builds and cut
down on the number of build minutes that
我们正在使用类似于 nullfy 的东西，这将有助于我们
we're using through something
like Nullify, which will help us
留在我们的免费层，保持我们的项目负担得起的东西。
stay in our free tier and keep things
affordable for us on our projects.
让我们添加对图像的支持,
Let's add support for images so,
这种饮料最棒的地方之一，就是它绚丽的红色？
one of the best things about this drink
is this gorgeous red color, right?
还有橘子皮，这是一种非常美味的饮料
And it comes with an orange peel and It's
a very aesthetically pleasing drink so
我们在这个网站上看到的并不是完全的效果
we really aren't getting the full effect
on this website when we're just looking at
文本，我们希望能够看到这些图像。
text, we wanna be able
to look at these images.
让我们来看看这些图片，我们可以看到
So let's get these going and the images
that we have are here, we can see
得到这些好看的图像，所以让我们得到这些网站。
got these nice looking images and
so let's get these into the site.
要做到这一点，因为我们不想真正拉长我们的建设长度,
To do that, because we don't want to
really elongate the length of our build,
我们要让 Cloudinary 帮我们处理资产管理。
we're gonna use Cloudinary to
handle asset management for us.
所以我们将使用一个针对 Cloudinary 的 transformer 插件
So there is a transformer plugin for
Cloudinary that we're going to use and
我们将利用这一点，安装让我们这样说
we will use that by
installing the let's say
纱线工作空间 negronis add,
yarn workspace.negronis add,
我们要加上 gatsby-transformer-cloudinary。
we're gonna add
gatsby-transformer-cloudinary.
为了获得映像，我们需要使用 gatsby-source-filesystem，然后,
And in order to get to the images, we need
to use gatsby-source-filesystem and then,
因为我们想要能够显示这些图像，我们要导入盖茨比的形象
because we wanna be able to display those
images, we're gonna import Gatsby image
这是一个反应堆纹身的辅助组成部分，会做很多
which is a helper component for
a reactor tat will do a lot of
延迟加载，直到图像在视图端口中才开始加载
lazy loading and it waits until the image
is in the view port to start loading and
所有这些美好的东西，以确保我们得到一个非常快的表演
all those nice things to make sure
that we get a very fast performance
而不需要我们做一堆手工工作。
with our images without us having
to do a bunch of manual work.
因此，我们将安装这些，而我们正在等待
So we'll get those installed and
while we're waiting for
我们可以跳到我们的盖茨比配置中
those to install we can jump
into our Gatsby config and
我将配置这个，我们将要
I will configure this, we're going to
首先安装 gatsby-source-filesystem 并
first install gatsby-source-filesystem and
对于选项，我们会得到一个名字的图片。
for the options,
we're gonna get given a name images.
再说一次，因为这是网站，而不是主题，我们可以更多一点
Again, because this is the site and
not the theme, we can be a little more
就像它是我们的工地一样，我们不必担心下游的兼容性
like it's our site, we don't have to worry
about incompatibility downstream and
然后，我们要使用的路径是源图像和
then, the path that we wanna
use is source images and
这样我们就能看到这些图像了。
that’ll give us these images here.
接下来我们要做的是，我们要用变压器
So the next thing that we wanna do is,
we want to use the transformer for
还有期权,
cloudinary and for the options,
需要输出 cloudname 我们的 API 密钥,
it’s going to need out cloudname,
our API key,
一个 API 的秘密和我们想要存放东西的地方。
an API secret and
where we wanna store things.
所以我们只需要选择一个上传文件夹
So we just choose an upload folder and
我会把这个设置成类似于校长工作室的样子。
I'll just set this to like
frontendmasters workshop.
要得到其余的这些，我们需要去 Cloudinary，所以我只是要跳过
To get the rest of these, we need to go to
Cloudinary so I'm just gonna jump over to
我会登陆 cloudinary 网站。
the cloudinary.com site and
I'm going to log in.
有一个非常慷慨的免费级别
Cloudinary has a really
generous free tier so
这是一个很好的开始形象资产管理的工具,
it's a really good tool for kinda getting
started with image asset management,
在你击中他们的帽子之前，你可以走很远的路。
you're gonna be able to go quite
a ways before you hit their caps.
一旦你在你的仪表盘上，一旦你注册了，你将在
Once you are in your dashboard,
once you're signed up, you'll be at
Cloudinary.com/console  ，我要到这里来，右上角的设置齿轮。
cloudinary.com/console, I'm gonna go up to
this, the settings cog at the top right.
然后我要去的安全标签和滚动所有的方式到底部
And then I'm going to go to the Security
tab and scroll all the way to the bottom
在 Access keys 下面有一个链接可以生成一个新对。
and there's a link under Access
keys to generate a new pair.
为了避免显示 API 标记，我已经创建了一些这样的标记
I've created a couple of these already in
order to avoid showing API tokens that I
然后必须去验证，我有一个禁用的关键，我可以显示代替。
would then have to go and validate, I have
a disabled key that I can show instead.
我们要拉的 API 键是这个，然后你就可以播放了
So the API key that we're gonna pull is
this one here and then you get to play
这个有趣的游戏与 Cloudinary API，你点击这一点，它变得可见。
this fun game with Cloudinary API where
you click on this and it becomes visible.
现在这是一个禁用的关键，所以这不会工作，但要选择它，你必须
Now this is a disable key so this won't
work but to select it you have to
移开，然后拖到这里，然后复制
move off and then kind of drag
over here and then copy it and
然后当你进入你的实际文件，它会有一大堆
then when you go into your actual
files it's gonna have a bunch of
所以只要确保你实际上只选择该文本。
junk on it so just make sure that
you actually only select that text.
这是一个非常有趣的用户界面怪癖，因为如果你试图真正选择它
That's a very fun UI quirk where because
if you try to actually select it it
会再次隐形。
will go invisible again.
(笑声)。
[LAUGH].
虽然不是很有趣但不管怎样,
So it's not very fun but anyways,
然后把它放到一个. end.development so 中
so you're then going to put
it into a .end.development so
我有一个活的 API 键在那里，所以我不会显示，但我会显示这一点
I've got a live API key in there so I'm
not gonna show that but I will show this
例子文件，这是完全相同的，除了我已经替换这些在这里。
example file which is exactly the same
except I've replaced these here.
所以云的名字会和你的 cloundinary 网站 Cloudbucket 匹配,
So the cloud name is gonna match
your cloundinary.com Cloudbucket,
你可以在这里找到，所以我的是 jlengstorf，所以我把 jlengstorf 放在这里。
which you can find up here so mine is
jlengstorf so I put in jlengstorf here.
然后对于 API 键，它总是可见的
Then for the API key,
that's the one that's always visible and
那么 API 的秘密就是这个，所以这些是你必须设置的值。
then the API secret is this one here so
those are the values that you have to set.
一旦你设定了这些价值观，我们就需要把这些价值观融入到盖茨比的环境中,
Once you've set those values we then need
to pull those in to Gatsby's environment,
gadsby 已经安装了 dotenv，所以我们可以使用它。
Gadsby ships with dotenv already
installed so we can just use it.
所以我要进入盖茨比配置，在顶部,
So I'm gonna go into the Gatsby config and
up at the top,
我需要使用 dotenv，然后我们调用 config 方法
I'm going to require dotenv and
then we call the config method and
遵循盖茨比的模式
to follow Gatsby's pattern we're gonna use
Dotenv.development 而不是一个普通的.env 文件。
dotenv.development instead of
like just a plain .env file.
为了确保。 我们会安排好的。 节点 ENV,
And to make sure the .env pick set up,
we do .env.process.env.NODE_ENV,
这样当我们处于开发模式时,
in that way what will happen is
when we're in development mode,
它会接收到这个 env.development 文件。
it will pick up this
.env.development file.
当您处于生产模式时，您必须添加相同的密钥
And when you're in production mode,
you will have to add the same keys
都在这里面。 例如，您只需将其添加到您的部署管道中。
that are in this .Example, you'll just add
this to whatever your deploy pipeline is.
因此，如果使用 nullfy，则只需声明要添加的环境变量
So if you're using Nullify, you'll only
did declare environment variables to add
特拉维斯 · 詹金斯，不管你用的是什么，你只要
them there Travis Jenkins,
whatever you're using, you would just
设置这些环境变量，使它们在构建过程中可用。
set those environment variables up so
they're available during the build.
一旦我们拥有了这些，我们就可以使用它们，让我们看看。
Once we have these,
we can use them, let's see.
云名称，所以然后我们可以得到 API 的关键。
Cloud name so Then we can get the API key.
Envapi key.
Process.env API_Key.
还有一个 API 秘密。
And then one more for API_SECRET.
好吧。
Okay.
这些配置，我们能够实际上获得文件上传。
Which those configured we are able
to actually get files uploaded.
到 Cloudinary，我们将能够看到结果在我们的
To Cloudinary and we'll be able
to see the result of that in our
这里是 GraphQL。
GraphQL there.
所以让我们开始这个，纱线工作空间 negronis 开发。
So let's start this up,
yarn workspace negronis develop.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 好的，变压器的工作方式是
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Okay, and so the way
that that transformer works is that during
这个构建只是将图片从文件系统上传到 Cloudinary。
the build it will just upload images
from the file system to Cloudinary.
然后以资产的名称返回基于这个资产的名称,
And then it gets back in asset name,
and then based on that asset name,
云 URL 是，你可以这样配置 URL 中的所有内容
Cloudinary URLs are, you configure
everything in the URL itself so
我们可以说给我200,400,600,
we're able to say give it to me with 200,
with 400, with 600,
这使我们能够建立响应图像与酸痛的集合。
and that allows us to set up
responsive images with sore sets.
如果我给你演示一下它是怎么工作的，可能会更简单。
It's probably just easier if
I just show you how it works.
让我们看一下 GraphiQL 层，我们可以清除它,
So let's look at the GraphiQL layer and
we can clear this out,
所以我们现在可以看到，我们已经得到了所有的云 / 资产。
and so we can see now that
we've got all CloudinaryAsset.
如果我进入这些节点，我们可以看到我们已经得到了固定，流动，固定
And if I go into the nodes, we can see
that we've got fixed and fluid, fixed
宽度是一个盖茨比形象约定，用于设置永远不会改变宽度的图像。
width is a Gatsby image Convention for
setting images that never change in width.
如果你有一个虚拟化身,
So if you have an avatar, for example,
总是40像素宽，你会使用固定在40像素宽
that's always going to be 40 pixels wide,
you would use fixed at 40 pixels wide and
这样图像就会显示出来，根据这个宽度进行优化。
that way the image comes out,
optimized for that width.
如果你使用流体，流体是为了图像的可伸缩性取决于视口。
If you use fluid, fluid is for images that
will scale depending on the viewport.
所以，如果你想做一个横幅图像，你想使用流体，因为作为
So if you're doing like a banner image,
you wanna use fluid because as
视口变得更宽或更窄，你只想显示一个图像
the viewport gets wider or narrower,
you only wanna be showing an image that's
大到可以容纳当前的视窗大小。
big enough for
the current size of the viewport.
你不想像1600像素的图像压缩到
You don't wanna have like a 1,600
pixel image squish down to
功能手机300像素的视窗，浪费了很多带宽。
a 300 pixel viewport on a feature phone,
it's a lot of wasted bandwidth.
所以，如果我们进入这些节点，让我们进入流体
So, if we get into these nodes,
let's get into fluid and
让我们看看来源。
let's just take a look at the source.
从我们上传的图像中，我们可以看到一个完整的数组
So, from the image that we uploaded, we
can see here that we've got a whole array
图像资产传回来，他们来在200像素宽,
of image asset pass back and
they come in at 200 pixels wide,
461,646和650，因为我们设置了650作为我们的最大宽度。
461, 646, and 650 because we've
set 650 as our max width.
那么，让我们来看看其中一个是什么样子的。
So, let's just take a look at
what one of these, it looks like.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 这就是 Cloundinary 真正吸引人的地方
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: And this is kind of
where Cloundinary is really fascinating
因为你可以控制所有这些不同的东西。
because you can just control
all of these different things.
所以如果我把这个设置为800，图像会变得更大,
So if I set this to 800,
the image will come back much bigger,
如果我把它设置为喜欢一个不同的长宽比
if I set it to Like
a different aspect ratio so
比如说我想要长宽比为16乘以9。
let's say I want it to be
an aspect ratio of 16 by 9.
杰森 · 兰斯托夫: 我把它放错地方了，让我们把它移到这里,
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: I put that in
the wrong place, let's move it over here,
长宽比为16 × 9。
aspect ratio of 16 by 9.
所以我们可以添加任何我们想要的转换，并且
So we can just add any of these
transformations that we want, and
可以帮我们清理一下
it will kinda clean that stuff up for
us so
我们可以按照自己的想法，进行变形。
we're able to go through and kinda add
the transformations as we see fit.
而 Cloudinary 在飞行中为我们处理这些事情,
And Cloudinary handles that for
us on the fly,
我们不需要管理，不同的资产产生，它只是为我们做。
we don't have to manage the, different
asset generation, it just does it for us.
这里有很多我不打算介绍的高级功能
And this has a ton of really
advanced features that I'm not gonna
进入今天，我鼓励你去探索云点。
get into today, I'd encourage you
to go explore the Cloudinary dots.
你可以做一些事情，如水印你的图像，你可以混淆的颜色,
You can do things like watermark your
images, you can mess with the colors,
你可以做 SVG 跟踪，你可以找到脸，你可以模糊的脸实际上
you can do SVG tracing, you can find
faces, you can blur out faces actually
非常非常强大的东西，是一个非常酷的 API。
really, really powerful stuff,
it's a very cool API.
但是一旦我们有了这个,
But once we have this,
一旦我们能够真正得到这个，然后我们可以开始在我们的网站上使用它
once we're able to actually get this,
then we can start using it in our site